Okay there are some important, important regulations when it comes to stepping over the sidelines of the piste.
So if in the course of a bout, one fencer slips over the edge, with one or both feet, a halt is always called by the referee.
So, in the event that in the action I slipped off with both feet, say I was getting a little overzealous in a repost and crossed over, lost my balance in a lunge, and ended up off to the side, a halt would be called.
If I had scored a touch, it would not count.
If my opponent had scored a touch, it would count, as long as it had happened immediately after I had stepped over the edge.
Now if I'd only stepped over with one foot, a halt would also be called.
The same rules would hold true, my touch would not count.
Even if we both touched at the same time, Siri would score a point, a touch, but I would not.
And if she scored a touch immediately after my touch, then she would win.
There is an exception here however, whereas if I had begun the action, before I stepped off the sidelines, which is to say if I'd established right-of-way, and actually legally begun the attack, in that case it probably would have been true.
If my armor had already been extended, and I had been in mid-attack and touched, even just after I had stepped off with one foot, the touch would still be in my favor.
So the rules get a little bit convoluted but it's important to remember, first of all, to stay on the strip.
Second of all, that it's better to step off with one foot, than with two feet, if possible, and also that the score will also go in your opponent's favor if you step off the, the piste.
So you want to remember to at all costs, keep your feet within the lines.